explore.org 2017-01-18

# 

Effective and revised as of November 4, 2015

Welcome to the explore websites. Because your privacy is very important to us, we want you to understand our practices with regard to collecting and using your information both online and offline and the steps we take to safeguard it. The websites found at [www.explore.org](http://www.explore.org/) and [www.explorelabs.org](http://www.explorelabs.org/) and any other explore website, mobile application, or application programming interface displaying this Privacy Policy and each of their components and subdomains and mobile versions if any, and the services, products and networks found at or related thereto (collectively referred to as the “Site”) are owned and operated by explore Annenberg, LLC (“explore”).

This Privacy Policy applies to Personally Identifiable Information collected from our visitors. When this Privacy Policy uses the term “Personally Identifiable Information” it refers to information that lets us know the specifics of who you are and can be used to identify, contact or locate you. When you register to become a registered user of the Site, you will be asked to provide certain Personally Identifiable Information such as your name, email address, and password. Personally Identifiable Information may also include your mailing address, telephone number, mobile phone number, and other identification and contact information. With this information, we can fill certain of your requests and better provide you with personalized services.

“Non-Personally Identifiable Information” refers to information that does not identify a specific individual by itself. This information may be compiled and analyzed on both a personal and an aggregated basis. This information may include the Uniform Resource Locator (“URL”) of the website from which you just came, which URL you next go to, what browser you are using, and your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address. A URL is the global address of documents and other resources on the Internet. An IP address is an identifier for a computer or device on a Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol (“TCP/IP”) network, such as the Internet. Networks use the TCP/IP protocol to route information based on the IP address of the destination. In other words, an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the Internet, allowing Internet servers to locate and identify your computer. Computers require IP addresses in order for users to communicate on the Internet, browse and shop.

We welcome any and all questions and feedback. For privacy-related issues, please contact us at [more@explore.org](mailto:more@explore.org).

### When we Collect Information

#### Personally Identifiable Information

explore may request Personally Identifiable Information from you when you:

  * Register as a member by creating a profile;
  * Comment on the contents of the Site;
  * Download or upload films or photographs;
  * Enter a contest or sweepstakes;
  * Participate in a marketing survey, promotion or event either online or offline;
  * Share media via email;
  * Correspond with us (e.g., Feedback);
  * Sign up for our newsletters or other communications, including text messages, from explore; or
  * Otherwise volunteer information to us.

#### Non-Personally Identifiable Information

The Site collects some non-personal information about you using clickstream technology, so it may not be readily apparent to you that it is being collected. Non-Personally Identifiable Information is not currently combined with Personally Identifiable Information.

### Use of Data We Collect

#### Personally Identifiable Information

At explore, we always want to provide you with the best possible web experiences. In order to do this, we use your Personally Identifiable Information to allow us to:

  * Process and track your request for our newsletters;
  * Send you promotional offers we believe will be of interest to you;
  * Customize our communications to you; and 
  * Improve the Site and visitor service.

Except as described in this Privacy Policy, your Personally Identifiable Information will not be shared with any third parties. By becoming a registered member you are agreeing to accept our newsletter and promotional offers and other communications from explore. Instructions for unsubscribing from any newsletters, alerts, promotions or non-transactional related emails are included in every email and in the “Your Choices” section of this Privacy Policy. If you sign-up to receive text messages from us, you may opt out of receiving such messages in the future by following the instructions provided in each text.

#### Non-Personally Identifiable Information

We use the Non-Personally Identifiable Information that we collect from our visitors in a manner that does not personally identify any individual. We use Non-Personally Identifiable Information to make the Site more interesting and useful to you. We also track the pages or documents accessed within the Site. This information is collected for systems administration and for analyzing and improving the value of the material available on the Site. Cookies are small files containing a string of characters sent to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser. explore uses cookies to store visitors’ preferences and to record session information. These uses include saving your password so it does not need to be re-entered when you visit the Site and serving content recommendations specific to your interests. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on the Site. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, you must enable cookies from explore in order to use most functions on the Site.

We may work with third party advertising companies and social networks, such as Facebook and Twitter, that may use information about your use of the Site in order to provide advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to you, including about explore, on their services and on third party websites. From the Site, these companies may place or recognize a unique cookie on your computer or use other technologies such as web beacons or pixel tags. Our Privacy Policy does not cover any use of information that a third party ad serving company may collect from you.

We use Google Analytics on the Site to collect Non-Personally Identifiable Information to analyze how users use the Site. For more information about how to opt out of having your information used by Google Analytics, visit https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/. Our systems do not recognize browser “Do Not Track” signals.

#### Our Contractors

We contract with other companies (such as website developers and advertising agencies) to provide certain services to explore, for example, to fulfill information requests and administer the Site. In some instances, these contractors may have access to Personally Identifiable Information, but they are contractually obligated to maintain the confidentiality of the information and to use it only for purposes of carrying out the business of the Site.

These companies are prohibited by contract from using this information for their own marketing purposes or from sharing this information with anyone other than explore, except as needed to provide services to explore.

#### Third Parties

Your Personally Identifiable Information is never shared with any third party except as described above to our contractors who use it ONLY to carry out explore business or elsewhere in this Privacy Policy.

### Disclosure Exceptions

Notwithstanding the above policies, we reserve the right to disclose your information including Personally Identifiable Information to appropriate third parties if we are required to do so by law or we believe that such action is necessary:

  * To comply with legal process such as a search warrant, subpoena or court order;
  * To protect the rights and property of the Site, explore or The Annenberg Foundation;
  * To investigate reports of fraud or of users sending material using a false e-mail address or users sending harassing, threatening, or abusive messages;
  * To protect against misuse or unauthorized use of the Site; or
  * During emergencies, such as when we believe someone’s physical safety is at risk.

### Your Choices

You may ask to review, revise, correct or update any of your personal information by contacting us at the address below. You may also request changes in your e-mail preferences, such as letting us know that you do not wish to receive further email or text communications from explore or if you wish to have your personal information removed from our e-mail mailing list. You may contact us with regard to these matters at [more@explore.org](mailto:more@explore.org).

Please be sure to provide us your exact name and address so that we can be sure to identify you correctly. Because mailings are planned in advance, it may take several weeks for your request to become effective. If, due to human error, you continue to receive unwanted communications, please contact us again and we will make every effort to correct the situation.

Please be aware that whenever you share information on any public area of the Site, that information may be accessed by others. In addition, please remember that when you share information in any other communications with third parties, that information may be passed along or made public by others. This means that anyone with access to such information can potentially use it for any purpose, including sending unsolicited communications.

### Links to Other Websites

Occasionally we provide links on the Site to our partners or other sites we think you will enjoy. These sites operate independently of explore and have established their own privacy and security policies. explore does not have any control over the privacy practices of these sites. For the best online experience, we strongly encourage you to review these policies at any site you visit.

### Security

It is our intent to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of information that we have collected from you. We employ reasonable security measures to protect the security of the information you submit to us. We limit the information we provide to outside companies with whom we contract to only what they need to carry out their responsibilities. When you request product information or create an account on the Site, your transactional information is transmitted in an encrypted format. We maintain the data you provide, along with a record of your purchases, in a secure database. We cannot however guarantee the security of user account information and other Personally Identifiable Information at all times. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, accidental disclosure and other factors may compromise the security of user information at any time. You provide all information to explore at your own risk.

### Privacy of Children on the Site

It is our policy not to collect Personally Identifiable Information from any person under 13 because we do not allow children under the age of 13 to become registered members or to submit any Personally Identifiable Information to us through the Site. If you are under 13, please do not attempt to register on the Site or send any Personally Identifiable Information about yourself. If we learn that we have inadvertently gathered Personally Identifiable Information from a child under 13, we will erase such information from our records as soon as possible, unless the child’s parent or guardian consents to our maintaining such information.

### Policy Changes

If we make changes to any terms or conditions of our Privacy Policy, the changes will be posted on this portion of the Site so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, to whom we may disclose it and what choices you have. Please be sure to check this page each time you visit the Site as you are bound by the version of our policies that exist on the day you visit.

For questions, comments or assistance, we invite you to contact us at [more@explore.org](mailto:more@explore.org).
